(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T14:05:01.088974",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
もう きみの こころ チクッとしちゃえ
Let's give your heart a little prick...
わおーんっ！
Aroooo!
「絶対無理」思い出しちゃいそう
It feels like I'll remember saying "No way"
だってみだってみ不安になるし
Because, because, I get so insecure
全然嘘つけないし
And I can't lie at all
だってだってみばか真っ直ぐだし
Because, because, I'm just so foolishly straight
目指すキラキラもきっとぼく次第だ
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
Bitter? I'm not gonna say I give up
じっとしてらんないし
I can't stay still either
だってだってみ動き出しちゃう脚
Because, because, my feet start moving on their own
1, 2, ステップアップ
1, 2, Step up
ちょっとずつ進めば夢の式解けちゃうの
If I take it step by step, I'll solve the dream's equation
なりたいぼくを きみが好きなぼくを
The me I want to be, the me you love
ちゃんと余りなく魅せたいの
I want to show you without holding back
あちっちゃっちゅ
Ouch-chuchu
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
I'm surprisingly so useless at this
間違えて悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Always making mistakes and worrying
でもきみに見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
I'm going to meet you, happy if we meet
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Cry, cry, love, and wag your tail
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
Please remember this hopeless me
もうどうしようとかたまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and sink down
案外いけるかもふわり浮島って元通り
But then float right back up like an island
ベットリがやめられないおそらってそれなんだっけ？
I can't stop being sticky, wait, what was that?
うっかりが止められないまた歩いて棒に当たるの
Can't stop blundering and bumping into trouble
1, 2, ステップアップ
1, 2, Step up
死んだふりしてるのやめてはいこっち置いて
Stop playing dead, hey, come over here
欲しいがるきみとあげすぎなぼくで
You wanting so much, me giving too much
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go even further
あちっちゃっちゅ
Ouch-chuchu
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
I'm surprisingly so useless at this
間違えて悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Always making mistakes and worrying
でもきみに見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
I'm going to meet you, happy if we meet
やっぱりひとりじゃだめなんだけど
After all, being alone is no good
集まってばかしてわおっちゃえば
If we gather, act silly, and howl together
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり」
See, I can always say "Welcome back"
ぼくはきみに伝えたいんだ 大いなるハッピー
I want to tell you about this grand happy feeling
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Cry, cry, love, and wag your tail
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
Please remember this hopeless me
目指すキラキラもきっとぼく次第だ
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだ
Bitter? I'm not gonna say I give up
加速メラメラでぶっちぎる次第です
Accelerating with blazing passion to pull ahead
はぐれずに希望へ大爆走
Racing full speed toward hope without getting lost
きみのこころチクッとしちゃって
Pricking your heart...
いいじゃん ハッピーじゃん
That's fine, right? It's happy, right?
「絶対無理」思い出しちゃいそう
It feels like I'll remember saying "No way"
だってみだってみ不安になるし
Because, because, I get so insecure
全然嘘つけないし
And I can't lie at all
だってだってみばか真っ直ぐだし
Because, because, I'm just so foolishly straight
目指すキラキラもきっとぼく次第だ
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
Bitter? I'm not gonna say I give up
じっとしてらんないし
I can't stay still either
だってだってみ動き出しちゃう脚
Because, because, my feet start moving on their own
1, 2, ステップアップ
1, 2, Step up
ちょっとずつ進めば夢の式解けちゃうの
If I take it step by step, I'll solve the dream's equation
なりたいぼくを きみが好きなぼくを
The me I want to be, the me you love
ちゃんと余りなく魅せたいの
I want to show you without holding back
あちっちゃっちゅ
Ouch-chuchu
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
I'm surprisingly so useless at this
間違えて悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Always making mistakes and worrying
でもきみに見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
I'm going to meet you, happy if we meet
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Cry, cry, love, and wag your tail
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
Please remember this hopeless me
もうきみのこころチクッとしちゃえ
Let's give your heart a little prick...
わおーんっ！
Aroooo!
もうどうしようとかたまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and sink down
案外いけるかもふわり浮島って元通り
But then float right back up like an island
ベットリがやめられないおそらってそれなんだっけ？
I can't stop being sticky, wait, what was that?
うっかりが止められないまた歩いて棒に当たるの
Can't stop blundering and bumping into trouble
1, 2, ステップアップ
1, 2, Step up
死んだふりしてるのやめてはいこっち置いて
Stop playing dead, hey, come over here
欲しいがるきみとあげすぎなぼくで
You wanting so much, me giving too much
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go even further
あちっちゃっちゅ
Ouch-chuchu
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
I'm surprisingly so useless at this
間違えて悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Always making mistakes and worrying
でもきみに見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
I'm going to meet you, happy if we meet
やっぱりひとりじゃだめなんだけど
After all, being alone is no good
集まってばかしてわおっちゃえば
If we gather, act silly, and howl together
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり」
See, I can always say "Welcome back"
ぼくはきみに伝えたいんだ 大いなるハッピー
I want to tell you about this grand happy feeling
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
Cry, cry, love, and wag your tail
わおーわおーだ叫んじゃえ
Aroo-aroo, let out a shout
だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
Please remember this hopeless me
目指すキラキラもきっとぼく次第だ
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだ
Bitter? I'm not gonna say I give up
加速メラメラでぶっちぎる次第です
Accelerating with blazing passion to pull ahead
はぐれずに希望へ大爆走
Racing full speed toward hope without getting lost
きみのこころチクッとしちゃって
Pricking your heart...
いいじゃん ハッピーじゃん
That's fine, right? It's happy, right?
赤井はあと
Akai Haato
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
桃鈴ねね
Momosuzu Nene
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
ラプラス・ダークネス
Laplace Darkness
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
??????
「さあ、ホロライブアイランドへ向かうぞ！」
"Now, let's head to Hololive Island!"
「な、なんだ！？舵が切れねえぞ！？うわああああっ！」
"Wh-What?! The rudder won't turn?! Uwaaaaaah!"
航海をしていたキミたちが漂流したのは「こんこよアイランド」。
The place where you drifted on your voyage is "Konkoyo Island."
癖の強い原住民たちがいそうな雰囲気のするこの島に、キミたちは勇ましも足を踏み入れるのだった。
You bravely stepped foot onto this island, which felt like it had eccentric natives.
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is another wild commotion!
ようこそジャパリパークへ
Welcome to Japari Park!
がー！
Grrr!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ
Laugh out loud and we're friends!
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even when we fight and make a mess, we're best friends!
けものは居ても のけものはいない
There are beasts here, but no outcasts!
本当の愛はここにある
True love is right here!
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Come on, hold hands with me for a grand adventure!
ワン、ツー、スリー
One, two, three!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is another wild commotion!
姿形も十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has their own unique look, that's why we're drawn to each other!
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When we gently overlap our fingers in the twilight sky...
はじめまして 初めまして
Nice to meet you, nice to meet you!
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you!
がー！
Grrr!
振り向けば あちらこちらでトラブル
Look around and there's trouble everywhere!
なんてこった てんでバラバラ ちんぷんかんぷんまとまんない
Oh gosh, everyone's all over the place, it's total nonsense!
けものだから 大目に見ててね
We're beasts, so please forgive us!
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone is living freely!
そう 君も飾らなくて大丈夫
Yes, you don't need to put up a front either!
はいどうぞ！
Here you go!
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you, Japari Park!
今日からは どうぞよろしくね
From today on, please treat us well!
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔 君を待っていたの
Always with a gentle smile, we've been waiting for you!
開かれたゲート 夢をいっぱい語ったら
Once the gate opens and we talk endlessly about our dreams...
どこまででも 続いてく グレートジャーニー
The Great Journey continues on and on!
東へほえろ 西へほえろ
Roar to the east, roar to the west!
世界中に 響け サファリメロディ
Echo throughout the world, Safari Melody!
-Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
——Welcome to Japari Park!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is another wild commotion!
姿形も十人十色 だから魅かれ合うの
Everyone has their own unique look, that's why we're drawn to each other!
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When we gently overlap our fingers in the twilight sky...
はじめまして 初めまして 君をもっと知りたいな
Nice to meet you, I want to know more about you!
がー！
Grrr!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la...
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la...
集まれ友達
Gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la...
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la...
素敵な旅立ち ようこそジャパリパーク！
A wonderful departure! Welcome to Japari Park!
派手な歓迎を受けたキミたちは、戸惑いながらも森の奥へ。
Having received such a flashy welcome, you head deeper into the forest, feeling bewildered.
惑いながらも森の奥へ。
Deeper into the forest, still wandering.
待ち受けていたのは、甘い香りと怪しい雰囲気の小屋？
Waiting for them was a sweet-scented, suspicious-looking hut?
這いよりますか？生のうねり
Are you ready? The undulation of life
（破ッ）
Ha!
誰だ？邪魔するな my my LOVE
Who is it? Don't disturb me, my my LOVE
浅き深きものどもよ
You shallow and deep beings
（破ッ）
Ha!
誰だ？守り抜け my my LOVE
Who is it? Protect it, my my LOVE
（破ッ）
Ha!
馬が蹴りしものどもよ
You beings kicked by horses
（破ッ）
Ha!
理性が千切れる瞬間
The moment logic is torn apart
限界みたいだよ？
It seems like the limit, doesn't it?
理性がぶっ飛ぶ瞬間
The moment logic blows away
あなたは逃げられない！
You cannot escape
（逃がさない）
I won't let you escape!
（破ッ）
Ha!
そうだ！邪魔するな bye bye LIFE
That's right, don't disturb, bye bye LIFE
（破ッ）
Ha!
去ねよ喰らうものどもよ
Begone, you beings who devour
（破ッ）
Ha!
そうだ！あきらめろ bye bye LIFE
That's right, give up, bye bye LIFE
（破ッ）
Ha!
お餅焼きしものどもよ
You beings who toast rice cakes
（破ッ）
Ha!
「アノ子欲しいよ」「あげない」
I want that kid, I won't give them to you
かごめかごめ宇宙式
Kagome Kagome cosmic style
(後ろの真後ろ)
(Right behind the back)
アノ子下さい無理やり奪いたいのが愛の本能さ
Give me that kid, wanting to forcefully steal her is the instinct of love
待って待って！いやだいやだいやだ！
Wait, wait! No, no, no!
恋は混沌の隷也
Love is the servant of chaos
現れし私はだあれ？
Who am I who has appeared?
選ばれし君の神ですよ
I am the god of you who has been chosen!
愛を製作戦いながらね
Crafting love while fighting!
とか何と言っても本当はこんなにこんなに大好き
No matter what is said, the truth is I love you so, so much!
這いよりますか？生のうねり
Are you ready? The undulation of life
（破ッ）
Ha!
誰々誰だ？押し付ける our our HEART
Who is it? Push it, our our HEART
恥ずかし恥ずかしいものどもよ
You shy and embarrassed beings
（破ッ）
Ha!
誰々誰誰誰だ？押し付ける our our HEART
Who, who, who is it? Forcing it upon us, our our HEART
這いよりたいたいものどもよ
You beings who want to get closer
（破ッ）
Ha!
理性が斜めの瞬間
The moment reason crosses diagonally
逆立ちみたいだね
It seems like a catastrophe, doesn't it?
理性が歪んだ瞬間
The moment reason distorts love
あなたを逃がさない
You cannot let her go!
(逃がさない)
I won't let you go!
(破ッ)
Ha!
そうそうそうなんだ！邪魔するぞ come come HELL
That's right, disturb us, come come HELL
不器用だったものどもよ
You clumsy beings
(破ッ)
Ha!
そうそうそうなんだ！無茶振れ come come HELL
That's right, break through, come come HELL
名状しがたいものどもよ
You have no other choice!
(破ッ)
Ha!
「アノ子食べます」「だめです」
"I want to eat that kid." "No way!"
花一門め宇宙へん
The first gate of the cosmic realm
(あふれ出しました)
(Overflowing)
アノ子食べますもぐもぐ酸いも甘いも愛のヴァリエさ
I want to eat that kid, munch munch, the variation of love which is both salty and sweet
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ 待たせて神話になれ！
Become one with the strange future of Nyarlathotep, making you wait in myth!
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ 愛すべき君の神ですよ
Become one with the strange future of Nyarlathotep, I am the god of you who should be loved!
愛を製作戦いながらねとか何と言っても本当はやっぱりやっぱり大好き
Crafting love while fighting, no matter what is said, the truth is I love you so, so much!
這いよりますか？生のうねり
Are you ready? The undulation of life
(破ッ)
Ha!
恋は混沌の隷也 現れし私はだあれ？
Love is the servant of chaos, who am I who has appeared?
恋は混沌の隷也 選ばれし君の神ですよ
Love is the servant of chaos, I am the god of you who has been chosen!
変な未来のニャルラトホテプ 愛すべき君の神ですよ
Become one with the strange future of Nyarlathotep, I am the god of you who should be loved!
這いよりますか？生のうねり
Are you ready? The undulation of life
(破ッ)
Ha!
チェックのキャミソールを着て
Wearing a checked camisole
今夜…ねぇ！遊びに行くわ
Tonight... hey! I'm going out to play
スウィートな服は宝物
Sweet clothes are a treasure
君は少し 恥ずかしそうね
You look a little embarrassed, don't you?
ハートのネイルのピンクは…
The pink on my heart-shaped nails...
ホントはちょっと、大胆よ
is actually quite bold, you know.
12時すぎのシンデレラだ
A Cinderella past twelve...
もっと夢見せて
Let me dream a little more.
もっとそばに来て
Come closer to me.
tonight 二人きり Let's Party!
Tonight, just the two of us, Let's Party!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一 可愛い子に 生まれたかった
I was born to be the cutest girl in the world!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回 言われても まだ不安だわ
Even if you tell me millions of times, I'm still uneasy...
あ・い・し・て・る?
Do you... love me?
カートにあふれてしまうほど 今日は…ねぇ!お買い物の日
To the brim with sweets, today is... hey! Shopping day.
スウィートな帽子と手袋
Sweet hat and gloves.
お洒落するとキラキラするの 大きなハートが欲しい
Dressing up makes me sparkle, and I want a big heart.
ホントはちょっと弱虫よ
I'm actually quite timid, you know.
シープのブーツ脱ぎ捨てて
Take off those chic boots...
もっと愛される SweetGirl 女の子
And be loved even more, sweet girl.
ねぇ目指したい from My Heart!
Hey, I want to stand out, from My Heart!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一 可愛いって 今日も言ってね
Keep telling me every day that I'm the cutest girl in the world!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回 生まれても 君に会いたい 本当よ
No matter how many millions of times I'm born, I want to meet you, truly!
さぁもっと盛り上がってる? ビックヤ─! セーの! イェイ! イェイ!
Come on, let's get hyped up! Big yeah! Say yeah! Yay! Yay!
まだまだ声出せるんじゃないの? もっともっと盛り上がってくぞ!
You can still use your voice more, right? Let's get even more hyped up!
やればできるじゃん! ありがとう!
See, you can do it if you try! Thank you!
ハートのネイルのピンクは… ホントはもっと、大胆よ
The pink on my heart-shaped nails... is actually quite bold, you know.
12時すぎのシンデレラだ もっと夢見せて
A Cinderella past 12, let me dream a little more.
もっとそばに来て tonight 二人きり Let's Party!
Come closer to me tonight, just the two of us, Let's Party!
Happy! fancy baby doll! Love me! fancy baby doll!
世界一 可愛いって 今日も言ってね
Tell me today too that I'm the cutest in the world!
Happy! fancy baby doll!
Love me! fancy baby doll!
何万回 生まれても 君に会いたい 約束よ
No matter how many millions of times I'm born, I want to meet you. I promise!
世界でいちばんおひめさま
The number one princess in the world...
そういう扱い 心得てよね
So make sure you know how to treat me right from now on!
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気が付くこと
Part one: Notice when I have a different hairstyle from usual.
その二 ちゃんと靴までみることいいね?
Part two: Be sure to look down at my shoes properly, okay?
その三 わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Part three: Reply to every word I say with three words.
わかったら 右手がお留守なのを なんとかして!
Now that you know, do something about my right hand being left unattended!
別に わがままなんて 言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish...
キミに 心から 思って欲しいの かわいいって
I just want you to truly think from your heart that I'm cute!
世界でいちばんおひめさま
The number one princess in the world...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
気がついてねえねえ
Realize that, hey, hey
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか
Somehow...
甘いものが食べたい！
I want to eat something sweet!
いま すぐによ
Right now!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You mean cute, right?
文句は許しませんの
Complaints are not permitted
あのね、わたしの話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと
Hey, are you listening to my story? Hold on...
あ、それとね白いおうさま様決まってるでしょ迎えに来て
Ah, and a white prince is a given, come pick me up
わかったらかしずいて手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, take my hand and call me "Princess"
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
I'm not saying it's selfish or anything, you know
でもね少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's alright if you scold me just a little
世界でわたしだけのおうさまさま
My very own prince in the world
気がついてほらほらおててが空いています
Realize that, look, look, our hands are empty
無口で無愛想なおうさまさまもうどうして！
Reticent and blunt prince, come on, why!
気がついてよ早く
Just notice it soon!
ぜったいキミはわかってない！
You definitely don't understand!
わかってないわ……
You really don't understand...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Shortcake with a strawberry on top
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
Pudding made with well-selected eggs
みんなみんな我慢します……
Everything, everything, I will hold myself back...
わがままだとお思いないで
Don't think that I'm a selfish girl
わたしだってやればできるもん後で後悔するわよ
Even I can do it if I try, you'll regret it later!
当然です！だってわたしは
Naturally! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
ちゃんと見ててよね
See me clearly, okay?
どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Shall I go somewhere?
ふいに抱きしめられた
Suddenly I was held tightly
急にそんな！えっ？
It was so abrupt, eh?
「擦かれる 危ないよ」
"It's dangerous, you'll get hurt"
そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ……こっちの方が危ないわよ
So saying, you look away... I think this side is more dangerous
一瞬SAN値ピンチになりつつも思わずコールをしてしまった。
Though my SAN value temporarily dropped, I couldn't help calling out.
こんこよアイランドに体がなじんできたようだな。
My body has finally gotten used to Konkoyo Island.
ここは？アニマルパーク？
What is this place? Animal Park?
観光名所かな？遊んでいこう。
Is this a sightseeing spot? Let's go play.
もうみみのこころちくっとしちゃえ
Give your heart a little prick
わおーん！
Waon!
アニマルパークへようこそ！
Welcome to Animal Park!
まずは一緒にわおんしようね！
First, let's do a "waon" together!
「絶対無理」思っちゃうし
Thinking "that's totally impossible"
だってだって不安だし
Because, because I'm anxious
全然嘘つけないし
And I can't tell lies at all
だってだってバカまっすぐだし
Because, because I'm foolishly straightforward
目指すキラキラきっと僕しだいだピター？
Aiming for sparkle, it's up to me, bitter?
ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
I won't say things like give up!
じっとしてらんないし
I can't just stay still
だってだって動いちゃう足
Because, because my feet start moving
ワンステップ！ちょっとずつ進めば夢の式典けちゃうの
One step! Advancing little by little, we'll reach the dream celebration
なりたいぼくをきみがすきなぼくをちゃんとあまりなく見せたいの
I want to show you the me I want to be, the me you love, without holding back
びっくりするほどできないじゃん間違って悩んでばっかりじゃん
I can't do it as much as I'd be surprised, I'm just making mistakes and worrying
けどきみに見つけてほしくて
But I wanted you to find me
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ出逢えたならハッピー
I'm going to go welcome you, if we could meet, that's happy
わ！わ！叫んじゃえ泣いて鳴いて愛して尻尾振って
Wa! Wa! Shout it out, crying, calling out, loving, wagging tails
だからぼくをどうか覚えておいてもうきみのこころちくっとしちゃえ
So please remember me, and give your heart a little prick
もうどうしようとかたまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes thinking "what should I do" and feeling down
案外いけるかもふわり浮かんでまっだだぁり
Maybe we can do it, floating softly and relaxing
ベッタリがやめられないおすわりってそれなんだっけ？
Can't stop being clingy, what was 'sit' again?
エビバディ→解体！
Everybody → Disassemble!
思い出に消しゴム!? あれっ。
An eraser for memories!? Huh.
うっかりが止められない また歩いて柱に当たるの
I keep getting clumsy and bumping into poles again.
ワンワンステップファシン　死んだふりしてるの?
One-two step fashion, pretending to be dead?
やめて！はいこっちおいで！
Stop it! Hey, come over here!
欲しがるきみと甘えすぎなぼくで　もっといける気がしています
With a needy you and an over-pampering me, I feel like we can go further.
ちょっちょびっくりするほどできないじゃん
Wait, we can't do this as well as we'd expect, can we?
間違って悩んでばっかりじゃん
We're always making mistakes and worrying!
けどきみに見つけてほしくて　ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ　出逢えたならハッピー
I want you to find me, so I'll go meet you. If we meet, it's happy!
だってやっぱりひとりじゃダメだけど　集まってバシャしてわっちゃえば
Being alone isn't enough, but if we gather and make a fuss...
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり」　ぼくはきみに伝えたいんだ　大いなるハッピー
We can always say "Welcome back." I want to tell you: a grand happy!
ワワワンだったって賢者へ　泣いて泣いて愛して尻尾振って
To the wise ones who said bow-wow-wow, crying, loving, wagging tails,
ワワワンだったって賢者へ　だめなぼくをどうか覚えておいて
To the wise ones who said bow-wow-wow, please remember my useless self.
目指すキラキラきっと僕次第だ　ピカー？ギタブなんて言わないんだ
Aiming for sparkle is up to me. Flash? Don't say give up.
加速メラメラでぶっ切る次第だ　はぐれずに希望へと爆走
Accelerating ablaze to cut right through, rushing full speed toward hope.
きみのココロチクッとしちゃって　いいじゃんハッピーじゃん
Pricking your heart just a little—isn't it good, isn't it happy?
エビバディ→解体！思い出に消しゴム!? あれっ。
Everybody → Disassemble! An eraser for memories!? Huh.
ハイになる?廃になる?はい、とは言えない～!!
Getting high? Burning out? Well, I can't say yes!
お可視い世界 お菓子は消えちゃいどうしよ “どうして!?”も“ああして!!”も 君らしくないな?
A sweet world where treats vanish—neither "Why" nor "Do this" is you!
そんな時代でいいよ　僕らまだ“ワンダー”信じてるの No no no no!
That era is fine. We still believe in wonder, no no no no!
おとなたちの鋭利な目盛り　悩まされすぎちゃって　寄り目になっちゃいそーね!!
Adults' sharp scales, worrying so much you'll go cross-eyed!
どうしてあーしても全部だいすきがしいじゃん！！　みんなみんな笑っちゃえの魂胆で
No matter what, loving it all is fine! With a scheme to make everyone laugh,
宿敵　逆境　モンスター呼んだっていいじゃん!?　スットンキョウでサイキョウなセカイを
It's fine to call monsters! A quirky and strongest world,
どうにもこうにも救えない困難もいいじゃん!!　みんなみんな救っちゃお！のポーズで
Even impossible difficulties are fine! With the pose of saving everyone!
ちょっとやそっとじゃ崩れない笑顔どうじゃん！　100回オチても不死鳥は鳥乱さない
A break-resistant smile! After 100 falls, the phoenix keeps its cool.
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー　エビバディ ショウタイム！
One-two with bow-wows, three-four, everybody showtime!
デモデモセンセイ！答案は散々！うわー！　ハイ終わる?ファイナル?　0点じゃないならOK！
But teacher! Answers are a mess! As long as it's not zero, OK!
マルバツ全部一切合切ウチューしよう！　正解も不正解も大切なメモリー　つまずく日もあるよ
Embrace circles and crosses! Both correct and incorrect are precious.
君はまだ“ワンダー”否定してるの No no no no!
You are still denying wonder, no no no no!
解体する前にきいてよ待って！　トンガリすぎちゃう斜界に　ツッコんで、トンで、もう一回!?
Listen before you dismantle! Into society, tsukkomi, jump, again!
成功失敗も全部だいすき！でいいじゃん！！　みんなみんなウチューしよ？の魂胆で
Success or failure, loving it all is fine! With a scheme to unite in space,
だってだって君ももっと笑えたじゃん!?　スットンキョウでサイキョウな僕らは　まだまだ
Because you could smile more! We, quirky and strongest, still...
まだまだ消さないで!?未来はここからじゃん!!　みんなみんな一緒しよ！のポーズで
Don't erase it yet! The future starts here! Everyone together!
ちょっとやそっとじゃ崩れない笑顔どうじゃん！　100回トンダラトンデモお菓子なセカイ　ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー　エビバディ ショウタイム！
A solid smile! 100 jumps to a sweet world. Showtime!
ツッコんで、トンで、ドッカンで、ツンでも一回！　ツッコんで、トンで、ドッカンで、ツンでも一回！
Tsukkomi, jump, bang, tsun once again!
3, 2, 1, ミステイク！
3, 2, 1, Mistake!
セカイ解体10秒前!?待って待って待って　まだまだ一緒しよ？の魂胆です
10 seconds before world dismantling! Wait. Still be together?
101回目のそんな小指拝借　“ハッピーも失敗も消さないから!!”
101st pinky promise—"Because I won't erase happiness or failure!!"
セカイウチュウ未来超だいすきでギューじゃん！　みんなみんな笑っちゃえの正解は
World, future, super-love and a hug! Where everyone laughs is...
宿敵　逆境　モンスター何だっていいじゃん!?　スットンキョウでサイキョウお菓子だろ?
Rivals, adversity, monsters, anything is fine! A quirky sweet, right?
旋回満開もう一度だいすきでギューじゃん！　みんなみんなくすぐっちゃえ！のポーズで
Full-circle blooming, love and a hug! Tickle everyone!
ぜったいぜったいね、消せない笑顔どうじゃん！　100回オチても不思議は取り壊せない！
An uneraseable smile! Even after 100 falls, wonder stands!
ワンワンでツーカーでスリーフォー　エビバディ ショウタイム！
One-two with bow-wows, three-four, everybody showtime!
わんわん！ショータイム！わぁ〜楽しかったなぁ〜ケモ耳最高ー！
Bow-wow! Showtime! That was so fun~ Animal ears are the best!
…こぽん。こんこよアイランド、いいところじゃないか。
...Kopon. Konkoyo Island is quite a nice place, isn't it?
ってあれ?あの子、アニマルパークにいた子じゃ?追ってみよう
Huh? Isn't that girl from the animal park? Let's follow her.
オリジナルじゃなくてもいい　僕を見てくれますか?
It doesn't have to be original. Will you look at me?
ファジーネーブルの匂いで　私どこかに行けそう
With the scent of a Fuzzy Navel, I feel I can go somewhere.
ファジージェネブルの匂いで
With the scent of Fuzzy Navel
私どこかに行けそう
I feel like I can go somewhere
甘い苦い切ない想いを
Sweet, bitter, painful feelings
飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink them all up
真面目すぎるその姿が好き
I love how overly earnest you are
私には似合わない
It doesn't suit me at all
それでも横にいられたらと
Even so, if I could stay by your side
そう思う、いやそうやって思ってる
I think so, no, that's what I'm thinking
もう何回も呼んでいる君の名前も
Your name, which I've called countless times
もう何回も夢に見た2人の世界も
The world of the two of us, which I've dreamed of countless times
もう何回も何回も諦めようとして
Countless, countless times, trying to give up
戻って君に酔ってしまう
I go back and get drunk on you
私になってゆく
Becoming myself
ファジージェネブルの匂いで
With the scent of Fuzzy Navel
私どこかに行けそう
I feel like I can go somewhere
許すたび心まで
Every time I forgive, even my heart
オレンジ色に染まる
Is dyed orange
ファジージェネブルの匂いで
With the scent of Fuzzy Navel
君とどこか飛んでいけそう
It feels like I could fly somewhere with you
甘い苦い切ない想いを
Sweet, bitter, painful feelings
飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink them all up
悲しすぎるその結末はもう
That all-too-sad ending
私言わなくても分かってるの
I know without even being told
それでも横にいたいなんて
Wanting to stay by your side even so
そんなこと思えないよ
I can't think that way
オレンジに染まった5%の想いは
The 5% feelings dyed orange
私の思い出に溶けてしまう
Dissolve into my memories
消えてしまう前に
Before they disappear
ファジージェネブルの匂いで
With the scent of Fuzzy Navel
私どこかに行けそう
I feel like I can go somewhere
許すたび心まで
Every time I forgive, even my heart
オレンジ色に染まる
Is dyed orange
ファジージェネブルの匂いで
With the scent of Fuzzy Navel
君とどこか飛んでいけそう
It feels like I could fly somewhere with you
甘い苦い切ない想いを
Sweet, bitter, painful feelings
飲み干してしまいたい
I want to drink them all up
はい、ということで、AIこよりが初めて歌に挑戦しました！AIこよりどうだった？
Yes, so AI Koyori challenged herself to sing for the first time! How was it, AI Koyori?
緊張したけれど、こよりちゃんと一緒に歌えて嬉しかったです。
I was nervous, but I was happy to sing together with Koyori-chan.
みんなも、こんな特別ゲストがいるなんて思わなかったんじゃない？
Everyone probably didn't expect such a special guest, right?
僕が特別ゲストだなんてとんでもない！もっと凄い方が
Me being a special guest is ridiculous! An even more amazing person is...
今こよりアイランドに迷い込んでいるみたいですよ。
seems to be lost in Koyori Island right now.
な、なんだって！？
Wh-What!?
あの方は――！
That person is—!
ポケモン、ゲットだぜーっ！
Got a Pokémon!
たとえ火の中 水の中 草の中 森の中
Even if in fire, in water, in grass, in forests
土の中 雲の中 あのコのスカートの中
In ground, in clouds, in that girl's skirt
なかなかなかなか大変だけど
It's very, very difficult, but
かならずGETだぜ！ポケモンGETだぜ！
I'm sure I'll get you! Pokémon, get you!
ポケモン GETだぜーッ！
Gotcha, Pokémon!
マサラタウンに さよならバイバイ
Bye-bye to Pallet Town,
オレはこいつと 旅に出る
I'm going on a journey with this guy.
(ピカチュウ！)
(Pikachu!)
きたえたワザで 勝ちまくり
Winning with trained moves,
仲間をふやして 次の町へ
Making friends and heading to the next town.
いつもいつでも うまくいくなんて 保証はどこにもないけど
There's no guarantee things will always go smoothly,
(そりゃそうじゃ！)
(That's right!)
いつもいつでも ホンキで生きてる こいつたちがいる
But these guys are always living life in earnest.
こいつたちがいる
These guys are right here.
(ピカチュウ！)
(Pikachu!)
たとえ 火の中 水の中 草の中 森の中
Even in fire, in water, in grass, in the woods,
土の中 雲の中 あの子のスカートの中
In the earth, in the clouds, in that girl's skirt—
なかなか なかなか なかなか なかなか 大変だけど 必ずGETだぜ！
It's pretty, pretty, pretty, pretty tough, but I'll definitely catch 'em!
ポケモン GETだぜ！
Gotcha, Pokémon!
たたかいつかれて おやすみグッナイ
Tired from battle, goodnight.
まぶたを閉じれば よみがえる
Closing my eyes, it all comes back.
(ピカチュウ？)
(Pikachu?)
ほのおが燃えて かぜが舞い
Flames burn and the wind dances,
鳴き声とどろく あのバトルが
That roaring battle echoes.
きのうの敵は きょうの友って 古いコトバがあるけど
There's an old saying that yesterday's enemy is today's friend,
(古いとはなんじゃ～っ！)
(What do you mean, 'old'?!)
きょうの友は あしたも友だち そうさ 永遠に
But today's friend is tomorrow's friend too, yes, forever!
ああ あこがれの ポケモンマスターに なりたいな ならなくちゃ
Ah, I want to become a longed-for Pokémon Master, I've got to be one!
ゼッタイなってやるーっ！
I'll definitely become one!
ユメはいつか ホンニットナルって だれかが歌っていたけど
Someone sang that dreams will come true someday,
つぼみがいつか 花ひらくように ユメは かなうもの
Like a bud blooming into a flower someday, dreams do come true.
いつもいつでも うまくいくなんて 保証はどこにもないけど (そりゃそうじゃ！)
There's no guarantee things will always go smoothly (That's right!),
いつもいつでも ホンキで生きてる こいつたちがいる
But these guys are always living life in earnest.
ああ あこがれの ポケモンマスターに なりたいな ならなくちゃ
Ah, I want to become a longed-for Pokémon Master, I've got to be one!
ゼッタイなってやるーっ！
I'll definitely become one!
ああ あこがれの ポケモンマスターに なりたいな ならなくちゃ
Ah, I want to become a longed-for Pokémon Master, I've got to be one!
ゼッタイなってやるーっ！
I'll definitely become one!
はーい！という拠点で、なんと、今回こうやってホロライブに紛れ込んできたのは松本梨香さんでしたー！
"Ha-i! And so, the one who sneaked into Hololive this time was none other than Rica Matsumoto-san!"
どうもー！さっそく、レジェンド松本梨香でーす！
"Hello! Introducing the legend herself, Rica Matsumoto!"
にかんねー！
"Nikan-ne!"
にかんねーとはですね、えー以前ホロライブのファンクラブの番組、ホロテスでご一緒させていただきまして、
"Speaking of 'nikan-ne,' um, we previously appeared together on Hololive's fan club program, HoloTest."
久しぶりだね。
"It's been a while."
そう、久しぶりです！元気？元気です！あけましておめでとうございます！
"Yeah, it's been a while! How are you? I'm good! Happy New Year!"
ちょっと痩せた？
"Did you lose a bit of weight?"
え、あ、あー分かります？ちょっとあのボンキュッボンに磨きがかかってたんですけど（笑）
"Eh, ah, ah, you can tell? I've been polishing up my hourglass figure, you know! (Laughs)"
えー、あの、あともう一つ、ちょっとアピールしたいことがあって……
"Um, also, there's one more thing I want to appeal..."
全然言ってるけど大丈夫？
"You're saying anything, are you okay?"
全然大丈夫です！ちょっと呼吸を整えて……
"Completely fine! Let me just catch my breath..."
息を整えていいよ。
"Take your time to breathe."
あ、ありがとうございます。
"Ah, thank you."
ふー。ありがとうございます。うんうん、何々？
"Whew. Thank you. Yeah, yeah, what is it?"
実は、あのコヨリ、今日で一つ大人になったんです。
"Actually, Koyori became an adult today."
え、どこどこと？ 大人の階段上る……え、何々？ あ、上ったんです、あの、要するにバースデー……え、ハッピーバースデー！？
"Eh, where, where? Climbing the stairs to adulthood... Eh, what? Ah, you climbed them, um, in short, birthday... Eh, Happy Birthday!?"
やった！はい！
"Yay! Yes!"
Happy birthday to you~♪ Happy birthday to you~♪
Happy birthday, Koyori—! ちょっとネイティブ出ちゃいました。
"Happy birthday, Koyori—! My native pronunciation slipped out a bit."
めっちゃ発音良かった！ Happy birthday to you~♪
"Your pronunciation was so good! Happy birthday to you~♪"
イェーイ！にかんねー、ありがとうございます！
"Yay! Nikan-ne, thank you so much!"
え、じゅ、じゅじゅもって、その、あの、年、あ、ハッピーバースデー迎えたってことで、
Uh, since you've just celebrated your birthday,
えーと、抱負、
um, your aspirations...
抱負？
Aspirations?
あ、でも、あの、今一緒に歌わせていただいて、ものすごいもうやっぱ声量にビクンビクンさせられまして、
Ah, but... singing with you just now, I was really blown away by your incredible vocal volume!
そうそう、あの小さいときからね、あの声は、あの本当にでかいんだよね。
That's right, since I was little, my voice has actually been really loud.
いやも本当にすごい！
No, it really is amazing!
もうそれを感じて、より、あの、歌今年頑張ろうっていうのが、もともと抱負だったんですけど、より思いました。
Feeling that, I felt even more motivated to work hard on my singing this year—which was already my resolution, but it made me feel it even more.
そうだね。はい。
That's right. Yes.
うん、そうそう。まあ、楽しく歌えばいいんですよ、歌なんて。あの、めちゃくちゃ楽しかったし、もうこれ。
Yeah, exactly. Well, you should just have fun singing, you know? It was super fun, and...
だってほら、あの、音楽ってやっぱり音を楽しむじゃんか。ね。
Because look, music is about enjoying sound, right? Right.
だからその、楽しむっていうのが一番のエネルギーになりますからね。
So enjoying it is the ultimate source of energy, after all.
いや、でも本当に一緒に歌わせていただけて、めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！ありがとうございました！
Yes, but really, getting to sing together with you was so much fun! Thank you very much!
よかったです。
I'm glad.
いや、なんか恐縮しすぎかもしれないけど。
I might be being too intimidated, though.
よくね、みんなちっちゃいころからっていうのよ。それちょっとね、どのくらいていうふうに思っちゃって、はい。でもありがたいですね、本当に。
People often say "ever since I was little," and I end up wondering just how little, haha. But I'm really grateful, truly.
ありがたいです。いや、本当にありがとうございます！
I'm so grateful. No, thank you really so much!
ということで、こここよラボというこよりのラボなんですけど、
So, this is "KoyoLabo," Koyori's laboratory, but...
バーチャル世界どうですか？
how do you like the virtual world?
え、すごい素敵！やんだ！
Wow, it's so wonderful! Yay!
でもなんかずっとなんかいろんなのが動いてて落ち着かないんだけど。
But you know, with so many things moving constantly, I can't settle down!
すみません、ちょっと。
Sorry about that, haha.
あのね、コンベアに、コンベアに乗ってみたい、そのコンベアに。
You know, I want to ride the conveyor belt over there.
え、乗ってくれるんですか？乗って帰っていいかな？
Eh, will you ride it? Can I ride it back?
あれに乗ったらもれなくこよりの助手君になれるっていうおまけ付きなんですけど。そうなんだ。
If you ride that, you get the bonus of becoming Koyori's assistant without exception. Is that right?
じゃ、りかね、今日からこよりの助手君ということで。
Well, Rikane, from today you're Koyori's assistant, then.
いや、じゃあいいわ。
No, then I'm good.
ええ！じゃなくっていいから乗ってください、あとで。
Eh?! Never mind that, please just ride it later!
ということで、ここよアイランドもこれからもちょっともうちょっと楽しんでいただければと思います。ありがとうございました！
With that, I hope you'll continue to enjoy Koyo Island a bit more. Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much!
ということで、松本リカねでした！ありがとうございました！じゃあ乗って帰ろうかな。
And with that, it was Rika Matsumoto! Thank you very much! Well then, I guess I'll ride back.
あ、乗っている。
Ah, she's riding it.
わ～、びっくりなゲストだったな～、楽しかった～！
Wow~, what a surprising guest, that was so fun~!
！？な、なんだ！？急に目の前が真っ暗に！
!? W-What!? Suddenly everything in front of me went pitch black!
そこに誓い立て！敗って捨てるような現実は
Make your vow right there! A miracle you'd tear up and throw away
一刀両断 叩き斬る
Cut it down with a single stroke of the blade!
終わりなき輪廻に迷いし恋だよ
It's love lost in endless reincarnation,
漆黒の翼でいざなおう
Let me guide you with wings of pitch black!
我ら エデンの星を滑るもの 秘密結社 ホロックスでござる！
We are those who glide across the stars of Eden—the secret society, holoX!
会いたかったよ 会いたかったわ
I wanted to see you! I wanted to see you!
会いたかった 会いたかった
会いたかったです やっと会えました
I wanted to see you! We finally met!
大好きって気持ちは 回って回って増えてく
My feelings of "I love you" go round and round, increasing more and more,
溢れて止まらない 君にちゃんと届くように
Overflowing and unstoppable, so that they properly reach you!
こんこよアイランド楽しんでる？最後はライブステージを楽しんでいってね！
Are you enjoying Koyo Island? Enjoy the live stage until the very end!
イェイ！ 1・2・3・4・5！
Yay! 1, 2, 3, 4, 5!
止まったままの ゴニン　すれ違う気持ち
Five people standing still, passing each other by in feeling,
君のその心が 溶かしていく
Your heart is melting it all away.
特別な形は 消えない奇跡描く
Special forms draw an unerasable miracle,
これからも ずっと ずっと 変わらないで
From now on, always, always, without changing—
大好きって気持ちは 回って回って増えてく
My feelings of "I love you" go round and round, increasing more and more,
大切なんだ 全部 一つ一つ抱きしめて
They are precious, embracing every single one of them,
ヒトの間だってほら 言葉を不二にしてゆこう
Between humans too—look, let's make our words undeniable.
溢れて止まらない 君にちゃんと届くように
Overflowing and unstoppable, so that they properly reach you!
分かり合っても どれもゆづれない気持ち
Even if we understand each other, feelings we won't yield to anyone—
何が大切かって 気づいてく
What is truly important, we realize step by step.
切り替わった形は 永遠の奇跡紡ぐ まっすぐな
Changing forms spin an eternal miracle, straight ahead—
君に 君に 光でてゆく
Shining toward you, toward you—
大好きって言い合ったら もっと もっと 高鳴る
If we tell each other "I love you," our hearts beat even faster and higher,
会いたいんだ 今すぐ はやる気持ち駆け出して
I want to see you right now, my eager heart starts running,
ちょっと待って止まらない ドキドキしてる 一瞬も忘れない
Wait a second, it won't stop, my heart is pounding, I won't forget a single moment—
あの日いつも夢に見る
The dream I always see on that day—
響かせよう
Let it resonate,
それぞれの日々の交差点で
at the crossroads of our daily lives,
遠くまで続いていく sky & field
stretching far into the sky & field.
みんなの歌の harmony
Everyone's singing in harmony.
環境が違うね 家庭や職場それに学校
Different environments—home, work, and school,
それぞれで頑張ってんだ
all working hard in our own ways.
しんどい事も泣けちゃう事もあるだろう
There are tough times and moments we might cry,
色々乗り越えてんだ
overcoming various obstacles.
Day by day
We’re worn out 心も体も だけど
we're worn out, both heart and body, but
Make your day
今日くらい 集まってさ 歌うたおう
Let's gather today and sing a song—
lalala Hey, let’s sing a song
lalala, Hey, let's sing a song!
この宇宙で 出会えた奇跡
The miracle of meeting in this universe.
lalalala 大げさだけどそうじゃない?
Lalalala, isn't that a bit dramatic?
なんて思うんだ and you?
That's what I think, and you?
経験の範囲で 出来る出来ないってわかっちゃうけど
We know our limits from experience,
まだまだ行きたいよね
but we still want to go further.
Time goes by
過ぎていく思い出は アルバムにしまって
stowing passing memories away in an album.
Time goes on 小さな一歩でもいい 日々を重ねて行こう
Time goes on: taking small steps, let's stack up our days.
悠かな時間が奏でるこの星はsymphony Ah
This star played by distant time is a symphony, ah.
幾億年のうちの一瞬を僕ら共に生きている
We live together for a fleeting moment among billions of years.
Hey, let’s sing lalala... この宇宙で出会えた奇跡
Hey, let's sing lalala... The miracle of meeting here.
lalalala 大げさなんじゃないよ
Lalalala, it's not an exaggeration—
これは僕らの奇跡
this is our miracle!
さあ 夢を 叶えるのは みんなの勇気
Come on... making dreams come true is everyone's courage!
負けない 心で 明日へ 駆け抜けていこう
With an unbeatable heart, let's run towards tomorrow!
それは僕らの奇跡
That is our miracle!
強い強い願い事が 僕たちを導いてくれた
Strong, strong wishes guided us forward.
次は絶対譲れないよ 残された時間を握りしめて
We won't back down now, gripping our remaining time.
ただの思い出それだけじゃいやだよ 精一杯 力の限り走るんだ
I won't settle for mere memories—I'll run with all my might!
chance for me! chance for you!
さあ 夢を 抱きしめたら 上を向いて 君の世界が 大きく変わるよ
Come on... embrace your dream and look up, your world will change!
さあ 夢を 叶えるのは みんなの勇気 負けない 心で 明日へ 駆け抜けていこう
Making dreams come true takes courage; let's run toward tomorrow!
chance for me! chance for you!
さあ 夢を 抱きしめたら 上を向いて 君の世界が 大きく変わるよ
Come on... embrace your dream and look up, your world will change!
そう あの日夢見たのはみんなの笑顔 君の笑顔さ だから笑ってよ
Yes... what we dreamed of was your smile, so please smile!
そう あの日おなじ夢を描いたんだ 輝く 瞳は 明日を信じてた
Yes... we shared the same dream, shining eyes believing in tomorrow.
熱い 熱い 期待の中で 僕たちは喜びを歌おう
In the midst of burning expectations, let's sing of joy.
同じ想い感じてみてよ 限られた時間を楽しもうよ
Feel this same emotion and let's enjoy our limited time.
もう止められない 情熱の勝ちだね 悔やむより走り続けよう
Unstoppable passion wins—let's keep running instead of regretting.
不意に見た空こんなにも青いよ 大丈夫 あきらめてないで走るんだ
The sky is so blue; it's alright, run without giving up!
dance with me! dance with you!
そう あの日夢見たのはみんなの笑顔 君の笑顔さ だから笑ってよ
Yes... what we dreamed of was your smile, so please smile!
そう あの日おなじ夢を描いたんだ 輝く 瞳は 明日を信じてた
Yes... we shared the same dream, shining eyes believing in tomorrow.
dance with me! dance with you!
そう あの日夢見たのはみんなの笑顔 君の笑顔さ だから笑ってよ
Yes... what we dreamed of was your smile, so please smile!
そう あの日おなじ夢を描いたんだ 輝く 瞳は 明日を信じてた
Yes... we shared the same dream, shining eyes believing in tomorrow.
負けない 心で 明日を信じてた
With an unbeatable heart, believing in tomorrow.
いま ここ で出会えた奇跡 忘れないで ぼくたちの 季節
Don't forget the miracle of meeting right here in our season.
最後まで駆け抜けるよ!
We'll run all the way to the end!
さあ 夢を 抱きしめたら 上を向いて 君の世界が 大きく変わるよ
Come on... embrace your dream and look up, your world will change!
さあ 夢を 叶えるのは みんなの勇気 負けない 心で 明日へ 駆け抜けていこう
Making dreams come true takes courage; let's run toward tomorrow!
さあ 夢を 抱きしめたら 上を向いて 君の世界が 大きく変わるよ
Come on... embrace your dream and look up, your world will change!
さあ 夢を 叶えるのは みんなの勇気 負けない 心で 明日へ 駆け抜けていこう
Making dreams come true takes courage; let's run toward tomorrow!
そう あの日夢見たのはみんなの笑顔 君の笑顔さ だから笑ってよ 輝く瞳は明日を信じてた
Yes, what we dreamed of was your smile, so smile—eyes shining toward tomorrow!
走り出せ 笑ってよ
Run out, laugh!
そう あの日同じ夢を描いたんだ
Yes, we dreamed the same dream that day.
輝く瞳には明日を信じてた
In our shining eyes, we believed in tomorrow.
負けない心で明日を信じてた
With an unbeatable heart, we believed in tomorrow.
今ここで出会えた奇跡忘れないで
Don't forget the miracle of meeting here.
僕たちの季節
Our season.
ねえねえ 今度のアイランドは楽しんでもらえた？
Hey hey, did you enjoy this island?
今日この日にこの島に流れ着いた君は運がいい！
You're so lucky to have drifted to this island today!
実はできたてほやほやのオリジナル曲があるんだよ！新オリジナル曲「New Journey」聞いてね！
Actually, I have a brand new original song! Please listen to my new original song, "New Journey"!
素敵だね ひとりじゃない
It's wonderful, you're not alone.
新しい旅
A new journey.
何を求められてるの？
What is being asked of me?
矛盾だらけの世界で
In a world full of contradictions,
何を信じればいいのか
What should I believe in?
彷徨い歩いてた
I wandered around walking.
どんな夢でもいいから
No matter what dream it is,
長い道のりを進もう
Let's move forward on the long path.
困難が待ち受けていても 仲間と乗り越えよう
Even if hardships await, let's overcome them with friends.
ひとりで迷い続けていた日々を
The days I spent wandering alone...
震えないでチカラ強く止めてみせるよ
Without trembling, I'll forcefully stop them.
初めて正義を共にかざせば
If we brandish justice together for the first time,
思い通りの光が真っ直ぐに飛び出してゆく 羽ばたいて
The light just as I imagined shoots straight out, spreading its wings.
忘れないでね この眩しさを
Don't forget this dazzling brightness,
希望に満ちた輝き 追いかけて
Chasing the brilliance filled with hope,
あり得ない景色に 辿り着きましょう
Let's reach an impossible scenery.
答え探しはいつでも
Searching for answers always
ぼくらを困らせるけど
troubles us, but
戸惑いなんていらない
We don't need any bewilderment.
今日から歩き出そう
Let's start walking from today.
汚れた空は綺麗に
The dirty sky becomes beautiful,
冷たい雨は消え去る
The cold rain fades away.
切ない夜が明ければ 風向き変わりだす
When the painful night breaks, the wind starts to change.
大きな雲を動かし 立ち上がり 両手広げ 走り出そう
Moving large clouds, standing up, spreading hands, let's run out.
扉を開けて
Open the door.
壊れた夢は拾い集めて 並べ替えたら 完璧だ
If we pick up broken dreams and rearrange them, it's perfect.
完璧を求めなくても
Even without seeking perfection,
ゆっくりと追い詰められて 悲しくても
Even if slowly cornered and feeling sad,
諦めないで続けよう
Don't give up, let's keep going.
白い月 愛しい星たちも ぼくらを照らす
The white moon and beloved stars also illuminate us.
初めて正義を共にかざせば
If we brandish justice together for the first time,
思い通りの光が真っ直ぐに飛び出してゆく 羽ばたいて
The light just as I imagined shoots straight out, spreading its wings.
忘れないでね この眩しさを
Don't forget this dazzling brightness,
希望に満ちた輝き 追いかけて
Chasing the brilliance filled with hope,
あり得ない景色に 辿り着きましょう
Let's reach an impossible scenery.
みんな、今日はこんこよアイランドに
Everyone, today on Konkoyo Island,
遊びに来てくれて、ありがとう！
thank you for coming to play!
観光のあとは お土産をゲットだ！ということで、
After sightseeing, it's time to get souvenirs! With that said,
大切なお知らせです！
I have an important announcement!
まず、今歌った新しいオリジナル曲「New Journey」は、
First, the new original song 'New Journey' I just sang
このあと24時から販売開始！
goes on sale starting at midnight tonight!
水瀬七さんをはじめ、たくさんのアニソンを
Starting with Nana Mizuse's music, and produced by
手掛けて来られた矢吹俊郎さん、大平勉さんに
Toshiro Yabuki and Tsutomu Ohira, who have worked on
作っていただいたアニメ白衣こよみのオープニングテーマ
many anime songs, it's the opening theme-like cool song
みたいなカッコイイ曲です！ゲットしてヘビロテしてね！
for the anime Hakui Koyori! Get it and put it on repeat!
そして、このあとすぐ！こよが作詞したオリジナル曲「Tear-Gazer」のアニメーションMVがプレミア公開されます！
And right after this! The animated MV for my original song 'Tear-Gazer' will premiere!
初めてのアニメーションMV、絶対見てね！
It's my first animated MV, so definitely check it out!
続いて、こんこよアイランドの観光お土産！お待たせのグッズ紹介です！
Next, Konkoyo Island souvenirs! The long-awaited merch introduction!
今回は海のレジャーセット！
This time it's a marine leisure set!
アイランドでの海の思い出を飾ろう！
Display your ocean memories from the island!
ももこママ描き下ろしの水着タペストリー！
A swimsuit tapestry illustrated by Momoko-mama!
そして、タペストリーを見ながら聞くのにぴったり！
And perfect for listening while looking at the tapestry!
いっしょに海で大はしゃぎボイスも発売するよ！
A situation voice 'Let's make a big splash at the ocean together!' is out!
続いて、海といえばキンキンに冷えた飲み物だよね！
Next, speaking of the ocean, it's ice-cold drinks, right?
こよとお揃いタンブラー！思い出を眺めながら美味しい飲み物を飲んでね！
A matching tumbler with Koyo! Enjoy a tasty drink while gazing at memories!
そして、出かけるときもいつも一緒！使いやすすぎるショルダーバッグ！
And always together when going out! A shoulder bag that's way too easy to use!
チャームや裏地もめっちゃ良いから要チェックだ！
The charms and lining are super nice, so be sure to check it out!
そして、バッグにつけてお出かけしてね！こよの水着パーカー衣装のぬいぐるみキーホルダーだ！
Attach it to your bag when going out! It's a plushie keychain of Koyo in her swimsuit hoodie!
フードの脱着ができる上に中にはちゃんと水着を着てるんだよ！
Not only is the hood removable, but she's actually wearing a swimsuit underneath!
のぞきこむなんてエッチ！
Peeking inside is perverted!
気になる全部セットには去年大好評だったこよが助手くんの誕生日をお祝いするASMRボイスの2024年海バージョンがついてくる！
The all-in-one set includes last year's hit ASMR voice celebrating assistant-kun's birthday, with a 2024 ocean version!
さらに直筆サインと複製メッセージ入りポストカードも！
Plus a handwritten signature and duplicated message postcard!
今回は全員直筆サイン書くよ！
This time I'll write a handwritten signature for everyone!
全員書ける機会はなかなか無いと思うので、この機会にぜひゲットして手に取ってくれたら嬉しいな！
Opportunities for everyone are rare, so I'd be happy if you seize this chance to get one!
以上、こんこよアイランドのお土産、
That's all for the Konkoyo Island souvenirs,
こよの2024誕生日記念グッズのお知らせでした！
and Koyo's 2024 birthday commemorative merch announcement!
素敵だね ひとりじゃない 新しい旅
It's wonderful, you're not alone on this new journey.
何を求められているの？
What is being asked of you?
矛盾だらけの世界で
In a world full of contradictions,
何を信じればいいのか
what should you believe in?
彷徨い歩いていた
I was wandering and walking along.
どんな夢でもいいから
Any dream is fine, so
長い道のりを進めよう
let's advance down the long road.
困難が待ち受けていても
Even if hardships await us,
仲間と乗り越えよう
let's overcome them together with our friends.
ひとりで迷い続けていた日々を
The days when I kept getting lost alone—
震えないで
do not tremble,
チカラ強く止めてみせてよ
show me you can stop it with all your strength.
初めて正義を共に掲げれば
If we raise justice together for the first time,
思い通りの光が
the light as we imagined it
真っ直ぐに飛び出して行く
will shoot straight ahead.
羽ばたいて
Spread your wings,
忘れないでねこの眩しさを
and don't forget this dazzling light.
希望に満ちた輝き
A radiance filled with hope,
追いかけあり得ない景色に
chasing after an unimaginable scenery—
辿り着きましょう
let's arrive there together.
答え探しはいつでも
Searching for answers always
ぼくらを困らせるけど
troubles us, but
惑いなんていらない
we don't need any hesitation;
今日から歩き出そう
let's start walking from today.
汚れた空は綺麗に
The tainted sky becomes beautiful,
冷たい雨は消え去る
and the cold rain fades away.
切ない夜が明ければ
Once the painful night breaks,
風向き変わりだす
the wind direction begins to change.
大きな雲を動かし立ち上がり
Moving large clouds, standing up,
両手広げ走り出そう扉を開けて
opening doors to run out with open arms—
壊れた夢は拾い集め
Gathering up broken dreams,
並べ替えれば良いから
arranging them is fine, so
完璧を求めなくてもゆっくりと
even without seeking perfection, slowly.
追い詰められて悲しくなっても
Even if you feel cornered and sad,
諦めないで続けよう
let's not give up and keep going.
白い月 愛しい星たちも
The white moon and beloved stars too
ぼくらを照らす
illuminate us.
初めて正義を共に掲げれば
If we raise justice together for the first time,
思い通りの光が
the light as we imagined it
真っ直ぐに飛び出して行く
will shoot straight ahead.
羽ばたいて
Spread your wings,
忘れないでねこの眩しさを
and don't forget this dazzling light.
生誕Live来てくれてありがとう！こんこよアイランド楽しんでもらえた？
Thank you for coming to my birthday live! Did you enjoy Konkoyo Island?
「大好き」と「やりたい」を詰めこんだライヴでした！！
It was a live packed with all my favorites and things I wanted to do!!
今年もそんな詰め詰めの一年に一緒にしていこうね！！助手くん、大好きだっ♡
Let's make this year packed full together too!! Assistant-kun, I love you♡